A Guide to the Papers of Emily Couric
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Emily Couric
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12986-d
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This addition to the papers of Emily Couric was given to Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, by Dr. George Beller, Charlottesville, Virginia, on December 10, 2009.
Biographical/Historical Information
Emily Couric (June 5, 1947–October 18, 2001) was a Virginia Democratic state senator from Charlottesville.
Scope and Content
The papers of Emily Couric (1947-2001) consists of ca. 2,132 items (8 Hollinger boxes, ca. 3.5 linear feet), 1985-2006, and undated. The collection contains drafts of articles by Couric [for the National Law Journal?] based on her own experience with joint custody of children and teenaged driver accidents; campaign materials; news clippings pertinent to her political campaigns and to her activities as a member of the Charlottesville, Virginia, School Board, and as a Virginia State Senator; State Senate speeches; letters of encouragement from friends and constituents after her pancreatic cancer diagnosis; memorial resolutions; letters of appreciation and condolence to Dr. George Beller on her death, October 18, 2001; and letters announcing memorial contributions to the University of Virginia Cancer Center Patient Support Services.
A series of framed items include a condolence letter from George W. Bush, a letter of support from Bill Clinton, and memorial resolutions from the United States Senate, the Virginia State Senate, the Virginia Democratic Party, and Scottsville, Virginia Town Council. Copies were made of these items before their return to the donor.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder heading and chronologically within folders. The notebooks of news clippings kept by Emily Couric's staff were kept in the order in which they were placed in the notebook, even though some date ranges overlap.
Contents List
- 1990 July-2001 July Articles by Emily Couric (Box-folder 1:1)
- 1993-2000 Campaign Materials, including a button "100 New Democrats to Watch" Democratic National Convention, Los Angeles (Box-folder 1:2)
- 2001 October 18 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 1:3)
- 2001 October 19 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 1:4)
- 2001 October 19 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 1:5)
- 2001 October 20 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 2:1)
- 2001 October 20-21 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 2:2)
- 2001 October 22 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 2:3)
- 2001 October 22 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 2:4)
- 2001 October 22 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 2:5)
- 2001 October 23 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 2:6)
- 2001 October 23-24 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 3:1)
- 2001 October 24 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 3:2)
- 2001 October 24 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 3:3)
- 2001 October 25 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 3:4)
- 2001 October 26 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 3:5)
- 2001 October 27-28 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 4:1)
- 2001 October 29-30 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 4:2)
- 2001 October 31-November 1 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 4:3)
- 2001 November 1-2 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 4:4)
- 2001 November 3-4 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 4:5)
- 2001 November 5-7 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 4:6)
- 2001 November 7-12 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 5:1)
- 2001 November 13-19 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 5:2)
- 2001 November 20-30 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 5:3)
- 2001 December 1-24 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 5:4)
- 2001 December 27-2002 September 17 Condolence Letters (Box-folder 6:1)
- N.D. Condolence Letters (Box-folder 6:2)
- N.D. Condolence Letters (Box-folder 6:3)
- 2001 October 18-December 20 Condolence Letters-Political Colleagues, including: George W. Bush, John Rust, B.J. Webb, James S. Gilmore, S. Christopher Hagin, Bobby Scott, Watkins Abbitt, Jr., W. Henry Maxwell, V. Earl Dickinson, Joseph Gartlan, Jr., Steven Landes, Virgil H. Goode, Jr., R. Edward Houck, Charles R. Hawkins, Brantley Bolling Knowles, Terry Kilgore, Joe T. May, Ronnie Musgrove, Charles J. Colgan, Richard M. Daley, Emmett W. Hanger, Jr., Jay Katzen, Hillary Rodham Clinton, H. Russell Potts, Jr., James S. Gilmore III, Tim Kaine, and Creigh Deeds (Box-folder 6:4)
- 1985 June 21-2005 October 7 Honors, Recognitions, and Memorials, including a letter of appreciation from Attorney General Janet Reno for her support during her nomination (June 22, 1993) (Box-folder 6:5)
- 2000 July 10-20 Letters and E-mails of Support Following Emily Couric's Diagnosis (Box-folder 6:6)
- 2000 Jul 21-25 Letters and E-mails of Support Following Emily Couric's Diagnosis (Box-folder 7:1)
- 2000 Jul 26-2001 October 17 Letters and E-mails of Support Following Emily Couric's Diagnosis (Box-folder 7:2)
- 2000-2001 Letters and E-mails of Support Following Emily Couric's Diagnosis - Political Colleagues, including: Russ and Emily Potts, Janet D. Howell, John S. Edwards, and Bill Clinton (Box-folder 7:3)
- 1985, 1994-1999 News Clippings -Miscellaneous (Box-folder 7:4)
- 1999 October 21-28 News Clippings- Miscellaneous (Box-folder 7:5)
- 2000 November 14-2006 October 18 News Clippings- Miscellaneous (Box-folder 7:6)
- 1995 August 3-1995 September 28 News Clippings copied from Notebooks kept by Couric's staff (Box-folder 7:7)
- 1995 October 12-27 News Clippings copied from Notebooks kept by Couric's staff (Box-folder 7:8)
- 1995 September 28-October 12 News Clippings copied from Notebooks kept by Couric's staff (Box-folder 8:1)
- 1995 October 29-December 10 News Clippings copied from Notebooks kept by Couric's staff (Box-folder 8:2)
- 1995 December 18-1999 August 31 News Clippings copied from Notebooks kept by Couric's staff (Box-folder 8:3)
- 1996 August 15-1997 February 25 News Clippings copied from Notebooks kept by Couric's staff (Box-folder 8:4)
- 1997 February 21-June 30 News Clippings copied from Notebooks kept by Couric's staff (Box-folder 8:5)
- 2001 October 18-2001 November News Clippings-Obituaries (Box-folder 8:6)
- 1996 June 12-1998 April 30 Speeches By Emily Couric (Box-folder 8:7)
- 1998 May 6-2001 September 20 Speeches By Emily Couric (Box-folder 8:8)
  Natalie Eller
  2020 March